EMMANUEL JOLAIYA AYODELE

Address: No1 Jagun street, Old Ife Road, Ibadan, Oyo State |Mobile: +2348143243024| Email: jolaiyaemmanuel@gmail.com |github.com/jeafreezy| Nationality: Nigerian | Date of Birth: 23RD March, 1998.

GIS/DATA ANALYST

3+ Years' success in leadership role, effective management and team collaboration

GIS/Data analyst, with experience working with spatial and non-spatial data and performing analytics that supports making well-informed decisions. Currently, I intern at Omooye IDSL, as a Geospatial Data Analyst, and my task ranges from overseeing the GIS operations of the Integrated data services organization to developing a database management system and setting up and enterprise GIS for their operations.

Highlights of Strengths

Time management(8/10)

-Fast learning and self-development (8/10)

Adaptability to working environment(8/10)

-Training and development(8/10)

Geospatial analytics(7/10)

-Critical thinking(7/10)

- Community Management, Capacity Building, mentorship/leadership(7/10)
- Effective management and team collaboration(8/10)

Career Experience

Temporary employee at Road-Preppers Technologies Limited(lara.ng)

Quality Assurance Personnel

My primary duty is to review the accuracy of data collected by field agents. Build an accurate road/trip fare that will be used in the organization system and ensure all data and information are correct and accurate.

Key Achievement:

- Used the best tools and practices to ensure all data are well reviewed.
- Supported my remote mapping with an on-site survey to improve accuracy and clear doubt.

Freelancing at Omo Oye Integrated Data Service Limited, Nigeria.

Data wrangler: (\$100)

The task was to gather data of all the hotels in Nigeria from a website platform and segregate them into different states in a spreadsheet. The job was to given on a basis of manually inputting the hotels data into spreadsheet and also to include their longitude and latitude coordinates.

Key Achievement:

• I succeeded in delivering the job before deadline by scraping the data from the website using python scripts and this automated the boring work of manual Input.

CMapit Studio, Ilorin, Nigeria.

Facilitator & software tutor (March, 2019-Present) (\$50)

I work with a team of GIS/Data savvy to provide quality and high impactful GIS/Data capacity building in research, academic and organization computation across various community in Nigeria. I am tasked to take charge of my local community by providing regular training for enthusiasts and spreading the gospel of the indigenous GIS software.

Key Achievement:

• Trained 25 GIS Enthusiasts, with little or no knowledge of GIS in a day, some of whom have shared their testimony of using the platforms in their projects and academic researches.

Federal University of Technology, Akure, Nigeria.

Association of Remote sensing and GIS students, FUTA Chapter.(ARSGISS_FUTA)

President(August, 2018-Present)

The presidential system at ARSIGSS FUTA is part of the overall programme that develops my leadership and responsibility skills. With the expectation to establish and maintain the highest standards of behavior, attitude and appearance at all times and provide a positive role model for other students.

Key responsibility:

- As the president, I was assigned the task to oversee all activities and affairs of the association.
- I was expected to understand and adapt to the wants, needs and troubles of all students.
- I was able to achieve this by luring student to myself who provide me with feedback from every nook and cranny of the campus.
- Constitution duty which am expected to abide by.
- I was able to achieve this by critically reading the constitution and ensuring all my operations and actions are within its boundary.

Key Achievements:

- With the work load of leading a total of 600 students, I am still able to attain the best result in my department and also my faculty.
- I was able to develop a website for the association. I happen to be the first president to make such great achievement and one of the achieved purpose of the website is bridging the gap between the associations' Alumni and the students.
- I was able to equip the association students with programming skills by collaborating with Developers Student Community FUTA.
- I was able to collaborate with YouthMappers FUTA and Farmsense to equip the associations' students with OpenStreetMapping for disaster response and community development.
- I launched a story map contest with the purpose of developing the interest of association students with online and web based GIS software platforms to meet up with the ever-dynamic world. Workshops and presentations was organized for students to present their maps and a price was given to the best presentation as a form of encouragement.
- I was able to achieve all this with the support of my fellow executives, fellow students, staff adviser, Head of Department and also with the support from collaborators.

Federal Science and Technical College, Usi-Ekiti, Nigeria.

Maintenance prefect (January, 2014 - January, 2015)

The prefect system at FSTC USI, is also part of the overall programme that develops my leadership and responsibility skills.

Key responsibility:

- As a maintenance prefect, I was assigned the task to ensure all schools' properties are well maintained and managed by students and also to provide weekly feedbacks on the state of each equipment's.
- I was expected to understand and adapt to the wants, needs and troubles of all student.
- I was able to achieve this by luring student to myself who provide me with feedback from every nook and cranny of the campus.

Key Achievement:

- With the work load of leading a total of 1200 student, I was able to graduate as one of the best 3 student in that year.
- Represented my school, in both local and regional mathematics / physics competitions.

Additional Leadership Experience

Association of Remote Sensing and GIS Students (ARSGISS) FUTA Chapter.

Welfare Director(2017-2018)

· Nigerian Association Of Petroleum Explorationist, Futa Chapter(NAPE/AAPG)

Treasurer(2018-2019)

· Federal Science and Technical College, Usi-Ekiti, Nigeria.

Class Captain(2013-2015)|Jet Club President(2014-2015)

Volunteer Experience

GLOBE Program, NASA

Water Quality Assessment of Ilara-Mokin River, Ondo State, Nigeria.

Assistant Project Lead and Data Analyst (December, 2018-April, 2019)

As a member of the Globe Protocol team, I'm part of a few people that believe in a world with sustainable, improved and clean environment at local, regional and global scales. The project focuses on water quality assessment at the local community. In doing so, I took part in a successfully carrying out a research on a creek in Ilara community and the results showed that the water in the creek is not fit for drinking as it was strongly affected by the sewage disposals and other anthropogenic imprints. I and my team successfully sensitized 40 villagers on the adverse effect of drinking unclean water and supported them with Alums and chlorine which were used for the treatment of their wells.

Key Achievement:

• I helped the team in making statistical and analytical plots which I produced using R programming language and this helped in understanding the correlation between the field acquired water quality physico-chemical parameters which helped in the decision making and supported our hypothesis during report phase.

GLOBE Program, NASA

Land Surface Temperature evaluation and estimation in FUTA, Akure., Ondo State, Nigeria.

Data Analyst (December, 2018-April, 2019)

As a member of the Globe Protocol team, I'm part of a few people that believe in a world with sustainable, improved and clean environment at local, regional and global scales.

Key responsibility:

- We were provided with an infrared thermometer to take surface temperature measurements around some selected lands surfaces (bare ground, marshy, tarred road and grass land) within the university campus.
- We are to acquire the data on a daily basis, morning and evening.

Key Achievement:

- I proposed the use of an Internet of Things enabled sensor to help with the data acquisition.
- I successfully analyzed the acquired data using Microsoft excel to create plots and chats that can be easily
 understood by a lame man, since the main purpose of all statistical analysis is to make inference and well informed
 decision from the results.

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH WORKS

- Hadejia-Nguru Wetlands Geospatial Mapping: Implication to its depletion and conservation.(completed)
- Flood Vulnerability Zone mapping using Remote sensing and GIS techniques (completed).
- Population estimation using Remote sensing and GIS technique(on-going)

Education and Credentials

B.TECH (FIRST CLASS IN VIEW) | 2020 | FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AKURE, ONDO-STATE, NIGERIA.

- · Discipline: REMOTE SENSING AND GIS
- · Related coursework: Global Positioning Systems, Field data Gathering, data analysis, Image Interpretation, Photogrammetry, Digital Image Processing, Cartography, Satellite Remote Sensing, Sensors, Hydrology, Land Use & Resources, Forest Ecology and Soils, Urban Design Theory, Image Processing Systems, Remote sensing Application in Geomorphology, Application of Remote Sensing in Urban and Regional Planning, Geographic Information Systems.

WASSCE, NECO, NABTEB, CISCO | 2015 | FEDERAL SCIENCE AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE, USI-EKITI, EKITI STATE, NIGERIA.

SELECTED ONLINE/OFFLINE COURSES

- Introduction to python for Data Science-Data camp (completed) The Ins and Outs of ArcGIS- Packt (completed)
- Cartography-ArcGIS online (Completed),
- Going places with spatial Analytics- ArcGIS online (in progress)
- The EOS Platform-Geo-University (completed)
- Data science/AI Boot camp -covens works(completed) Pgnosis(completed)
- -Do-it-yourself GeoAPPs- ArcGIS online (in progress)
- -Python for data science-Dataguest (Completed)
- -Cloud Computing 101-awseducate(in progress)
- -Open source GIS software Workshop-
- -World-Quant University (on-going)

Scholarship, Grants and Award

- NAPE/UAP Grants-in-aid award recipient (2019)
- Recipient of the Nigeria Federal Government Scholarship Award (2017-present)
- Recipient of The FUTA Alumni Association, Nigeria Liquefied Natural Gas(NLNG) Chapter Scholarship to deserving 300level student in the seven schools of the university.(2018)
- Recipient of Ekiti-State Scholarship Award (2018)
- Award of Excellence as the most brilliant student in the School of Earth and Mineral Sciences/Remote sensing and GIS Department.(2017)
- Award of Excellence as the Best Student in NABTEB External Examination, FSTC Usi-Ekiti (2015)
- Data science/AI Boot camp, cohort 8 at covens works, Premier Hub, Akure, Ondo-State, fully funded.(completed)

Organizations

- ASSOCIATION OF REMOTE SENSING AND GIS STUDENTS (ARSGISS), FUTA CHAPTER.
- URBAN AND REGIONAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS ASSOCIATION, USA (URISA)
- NIGERIAN ASSOCIATION OF PETROLEUM EXLORATIONIST/AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF PETROLEUM GEOLOGISTS(NAPE/AAPG)
- SPACE GENERATION ADVISORY COUNCIL (SGAC)
- NIGERIA GIS PROFESSINALS/GEOSPATION NIGERIA FORUM (NGP/GNF)

Certifications and Workshops

Open source GIS workshop delivered by PGnosis (March, 2018).

Technical Skills

- GIS: GIS softwares such as: ARCGIS (Desktop, Online), Quantum GIS and Remote sensing softwares (ERDAS Imagine, GeoDa ILWIS, ENVI), Smart GIS, Google Earth Pro, Openstreetmap, PCI Geomatica, Cmapit Studio, GPS, Stereoscope and spectroradiometer and Universal Map Downloader.
- Data Management: PostgreSQL, POSTGIS AND GEO SERVER.
- Data Collection: Kobocollect, ODK Collect, OpenMapkits
- **Humanitarian Contributions:** OSM ID Editor & JOSM, Map swipe.

Programming: Python(6/10), R(5/10) and SQL(3/10)

- Analytics/Report: Tableau, Google Data Studio.
- Intermediate user of Microsoft Office/Google(Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access)
- **COMMUNICATION**: Documentation & Report Writing Skills

REFEREES

Available upon Request.